Andrew Macheret

4754 Kings River Court • San José, CA 95128 • 650-630-0394 • andrew.macheret@gmail.com • andrewmacheret.com

SUMMARY

Polyglot full-stack engineer with over 8 years of experience. Often relied on to take point on large projects and risky prototypes, and take them to production. Self-starter with natural leadership abilities and strong interpersonal skills. Extremely comfortable at all levels of web development - cloud DevOps, database administration, high-level architecture, microservices, cross-browser UX, build & release pipelines, etc. Deep expertise with Java, Javascript, Bash, MySQL, Docker, AWS services, but not afraid to use the right tool for the job. Extremely quick learner of new languages and technologies. There are no language barriers.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Languages Java, Javascript, Bash, Python, Ruby, Perl, AWK, PHP, ASP.NET, VB.Net,

C#, C/C++

Notable Libraries React (+Flux, +Redux), ¡Query, Prototype.js, Spring, Guice, Hibernate,

Selenium, JUnit, Google Cast, Android, Guava, Apache Commons, Rails,

Django, .NET, MFC, Win32 API, DirectX, OpenGL

Project Management JIRA, Trac, Git, Subversion, Perforce, CVS, Ant, Maven, Gulp, Jenkins,

Make

Markup & Notable Protocols HTML, JSON, YAML, XML, CSV, CSS, REST, SOAP, HTTP, XPath, Regex,

XSD, WSDL, OAuth

Databases MySQL, Memcached, Redis, Elasticsearch, MongoDB, DynamoDB,

Oracle, SAP HANA, Sqlite

Servers & Services Node.js, Spring Boot, Tomcat, Jetty, IIS, JBoss, Apache, JMeter,

Selenium IDE, Graphite, Docker, Vagrant, PagerDuty, Hadoop

Cloud Technologies AWS: Lambda, API Gateway, EC2, ELB, RDS, ElastiCache, Elastic

Beanstalk, S3, Route 53, Alexa Skills, SNS, CloudWatch, IAM,

DynamoDB, ElasticMapReduce

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SAP	Arik	oa, P	alo	Alto,	Cal	liforni	ia
-----	------	-------	-----	-------	-----	---------	----

Senior Software Engineer ______ August 2016 to September 2017

- Built a fully featured docker environment for onboarding developers
- Upgraded the build system for 2.5 million lines of java (and 5 million lines of other files) from Make to Maven
- Made significant progress in migrating that same codebase off of Oracle 11g to SAP HANA

DeVero, Inc., San José, California

Senior Technology EngineerMarch 2015 to October 2015Lead Application EngineerJuly 2014 to March 2015Software EngineerJuly 2008 to July 2014

- Principal developer from the company's very beginnings, oversaw the company's growth from \$5 thousand to \$10 million annual revenue in 6 years, dominating the market.
- Mentored junior developers, working closely with them to help them grow and succeed.

- Developed features and functions at all levels of the web stack, including front end JavaScript changes all the way to backend schema design in MySQL, and everything in between in Java, Hibernate, JSP, Tomcat, Apache, and many other languages and technologies.
- Managed all levels of infrastructure Git and SVN repository workflow, Jenkins continuous integration server, Gitlab server, JIRA workflow configurations, build and release management scripts, Maven and Ant configurations, AWS infrastructure.
- Migrated the flagship application from Windows servers in a local data center to a fully AWS hosted cloud solution while maintaining strict HIPAA and HITECH compliance.
- Served on a regular basis as an on-call first responder in the event of outages and critical failures.
- Integrated and maintained REST and SOAP integrations with third party vendors.
- Established a testing framework utilizing unit tests, integration tests, and selenium tests, as well as load testing with JMeter and end user testing in Selenium IDE.
- Produced numerous prototypes that started as side projects and often became integral parts of
 the flagship application, such as using Hadoop and ElasticMapReduce to produce analytics on
 log files, creating a centralized portal for DeVero employees, and the collection of geolocation
 data for the purposes of user-facing auditing and reporting.

International Components for Unicode (ICU), IBM, San José, California

Software Developer Co-op ______ January 2007 to June 2008

- Assigned to the development and maintenance of ICU, ICU4J and ICU4JNI Open-source APIs for internationalizing applications in C/C++, Java and JNI respectively.
- Refactored, maintained, and ported functionality between C, C++, Java, JNI and Perl.
- Improved performance of the build system by 5x, encoding conversion algorithms by 2x, and locale data loading by 30x.
- Created an end-user tool for remotely updating customer copies of ICU4J with up-to-date time zone data.

Mathematics Department, San José State University, San José, California Instructional Student Assistant August to December 2006

 Assisted in the instruction of Combinatorics to undergraduates. Graded homework papers, wrote complete solutions for students to study from and coached and mentored students having trouble.

Tutorial Center, Foothill College, Los Altos, California

Academic Tutor _____ March to August 2005

 Tutored students in programming with C++ and Java in all skill levels, General & Modern Physics, Calculus, Differential Equations, Linear Algebra, Discrete Mathematics, and all lower division mathematics courses.

Continuum Lasers, Inc., Santa Clara, California

Web Design Intern _____ June to August 1998

• Overhauled company website, adding server-based scripts for Unix and client-based scripts in Javascript as well as redesigning basic outline of website.

EDUCATION

San José State University

- Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, 2008 work done, diploma not obtained
- Bachelor of Arts, Mathematics, 2008 work done, diploma not obtained

Foothill College

- Associate of Science, Computer Science, 2005
- Associate of Science, Mathematics, 2005
- Associate of Science, Engineering, 2005 work done, diploma not obtained
- Associate of Science, Physics, 2005 work done, diploma not obtained

COMPETITIONS, ORGANIZATIONS, INTERESTS

Competitions:

- Top 18th percentile at TopCoder.com Algorithm Competitions.
 - Ranked 2nd for San José State University in 2008.
- Top 200 in Microsoft Imagine Cup Algorithm Competition 2006.
- 2nd place in SJSU Math Department *Problem of the Week* 2005.

Organizations:

- Code Across, San Jose, Contributor.
- SJSU Computer Science Club, Treasurer.
- SJSU Chess Club, Treasurer.
- SJSU Math Club, Member. Helped organize various events and colloquiums.
- SJSU Physics Club, Member.
- Golden Key International Honor Society, Member.

(Ir)relevant Hobbies:

- IoT Raspberry Pi, Arduino, Particle, Alexa skills
- My website https://andrewmacheret.com
- My github https://github.com/andrewmacheret
- Ping pong
- Board games
- Half marathons
- Ice hockey

References available upon request.